Guide to the David Starr Jordan Papers SC0058
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Tributes after Jordan's Death, Series I-E
    - Series I-AA: Letter books, 1898-1910
      - September 17, 1906 - November 3, 1906 (Box 18, Volume 38)
      - November 3, 1906 -January 8, 1907 (Box 19, Volume 39)
      - January 8, 1907 - February 12, 1907 (Box 19, Volume 40)
      - February 12, 1907 - March 18, 1907 (Box 20, Volume 41)
      - March 18, 1907 - May 10, 1907 (Box 20, Volume 42)
      - May 9, 1907 - August 5, 1907 (Box 21, Volume 43)
      - November 14, 1907 - January 13, 1908 (Box 21, Volume 45)
      - March 11, 1908 - April 15, 1908 (Box 22, Volume 47)
      - April 16, 1908 - May 23, 1908 (Box 22, Volume 48)
      - May 23, 1908 - August 29, 1908 (Box 23, Volume 49)
      - August 29, 1908 - September 30, 1908 (Box 23, Volume 50)
      - September 30, 1908 - November 5, 1908 (Box 24, Volume 51)
      - November 5, 1908 - December 19, 1908 (Box 24, Volume 52)
      - December 19, 1908 - January 16, 1909 (Box 25, Volume 53)
      - January 16, 1909 - February 15, 1909 (Box 25, Volume 54)
      - February 15, 1909 - March 15, 1909 (Box 26, Volume 55)
      - March 15, 1909 - April 13, 1909 (Box 26, Volume 56)
      - April 13, 1909 - May 25, 1909 (Box 27, Volume 57)
      - missing (Box 27, Volume 58/59)
      - August 24, 1909 - September 30, 1909 (Box 27, Volume 60)
      - September 29, 1909 - November 10, 1909 (Box 28, Volume 61)
      - November 10, 1909 - December 15, 1909 (Box 28, Volume 62)
      - December 15, 1909 - February 1, 1910 (Box 29, Volume 63)
      - February 1, 1910 - March 14, 1910 (Box 29, Volume 64)
      - March 14, 1910 - April 26, 1910 (Box 30, Volume 65)
      - April 26, 1910 - June 2, 1910 (Box 30, Volume 66)
  - Jessie Knight Jordan Correspondence, Series I-F
    Prior to Jordan's death, his physical condition prevented him from answering his correspondence or managing his business affairs. Mrs. Jordan assumed this burden and since their interests paralleled she continued to correspond with and support certain organizations after Dr. Jordan's death.
    Mrs. Jordan frequently kept related correspondence together regardless of date. Such assortments have been filed in chronological order by the earliest date. Programs, invitations, etc. have been filed by the (earliest) date of the event. Within one date letters are filed alphabetically by sender; Mrs. Jordan's letters are alphabetical by recipient.
    - 1895 - 1928, December (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1929, January-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1929, July (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1929, August (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1929, September (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1929, October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1929, November (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1929, December (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1930, January-February (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1930, March-April (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1930, May (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1930, June (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1930, July (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1930, August (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1930, September (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1930, October (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1930, November (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1930, December (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1931, January (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1931, February (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1931, March (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1931, April (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1931, May (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 1931, June (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1931, July (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1931, August (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 1931, September (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 1931, October (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 1931, November (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1931, December (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - J.K.J. condolences, 1931, September: (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - J.K.J. condolences, 1931, October: (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1932 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - 1933 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 1935 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - 1936 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 1937 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 1938 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - 1939 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - 1941 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - 1942-48 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - 1949 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - 1950-51 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - JKJ notes on DSJ & JKJ (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - JKJ addenda (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Journals and Notebooks, 1870-1928; Series II
  - Journals, Series II-A
    These are in order by earliest date. The pocket journals and diaries ofter were used as scratch pads and generally contain random thoughts. Jordan was not systematic about entries, and therefore while these journals and diaries are a good source of information on abstract ideas, they do not reveal detailed daily activities of Jordan's life.
    - Pocket journals, diaries and notebooks, 1875-1929 (Box 1-6A)
  - Lecture Notebooks, Series II-B
    Arranged in chronological order, these include Jordan's notes both on lectures he attended and those he gave.
    - Volume One: Notebook: Systematic botany, 1870 (Box 6B, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      (Notes and sketches for a lecture class given by A.N. Prentiss, Cornell, 1870)
    - Volume Two: Color sketching of available plants in western New York, by DSJ, 1872 (Box 6B, Folder 2)
    - Notebook: Summer School of Science, Penikese Island, 1873 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Lecture notes and syllabi, 1892-1917 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Lecture notes and syllabi, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Student notes on DSJ's Zoology course, taught at Butler University, 1878 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Scrapbooks, Series III
  In chronological order by earliest date of each volume, they contain general clippings, biographical material and some of Jordan's writings.
  - Vol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 4 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 4 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 5a (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 5b (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 5c (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 5d (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 5e (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 5f (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 5g (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 6 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 7 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 8 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 9 (Box 10)
  - Vol. 10 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 11 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 11 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 12 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mexican scrapbook (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 13 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 13c (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 14 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 15 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 16 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 17 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 18, August 6, 1924-June 27, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 19 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 20: Indiana period, circa 1883-1887 (Box 10)
- Manuscripts, Series IV
  - Manuscripts and Bibliographical Material, Series IV-A
    - Hays bibliography (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hays bibliography: addenda and table of contents (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Additional miscellaneous bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 2a)
  - Manuscripts, Series IV-B
    This series contains Alice N. Hays book David Starr Jordan: A Bibliography of His Writings, 1871-1931; several other bibliographies; and manuscripts of unpublished or apparently unpublished writings. Also included is a segment of Series V, an unpublished addenda to Jordan's autobiography, Days of a Man.
    Items with a Misc. F or XF prefix relate to fishes.
    - Manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Misc. 91 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Misc. 109 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Misc. 114 (131, 184) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Misc. 124 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Misc. 125 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Misc. 168 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Misc. 201 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Misc. 306 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Misc. 313 (408) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Misc. 316 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Misc. 320 (410) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Misc. 384 (383) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Misc. 392 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Misc. 399 (452) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Misc. 410 (369, 351) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Misc. 421 (396, 351) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Misc. 437 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Misc. 443 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Misc. 496 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Misc. 534 (492) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Misc. 543 (496) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Misc. 545 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Misc. 646 (914) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Misc. 660 (816) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Misc. 675 (768, 747) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Misc. 705 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Misc. 806 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Misc. 828 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Misc. 846 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Misc. 943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Misc. 970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Misc. 1007 (109, 114, 131, 184, 57) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Misc. 1109 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Misc. 1133 (1180) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Misc. 1154 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Misc. 1155 (1179, 1180c) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Misc. 1159 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Misc. 1175 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Misc. 1178 (1155, 1141, 1147) (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Misc. 1179 (1180) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Misc. 1180 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Misc. 1184 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Misc. 1187 (1162, 1181) (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Misc. 1194 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Misc. 1220 (1225, 1223, 1255) (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Misc. 1225 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Misc. 1228 (1227) (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Misc. 1239 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Misc. 1258 (1284) (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Misc. 1267 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Misc. 1271 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Misc. 1278 (1274) (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Misc. 1287 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Misc. 1294 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Misc. 1323 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Misc. 1332 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Misc. 1335 (1154) (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Misc. (1347, 1149, 1335, 1154) (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Misc. 1355 (1251) (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Misc. 1356 (1308) (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Misc. 1359 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Misc. 1365 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Misc. F67 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Misc. F305 (F306) (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Misc. F359 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Misc. F438 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Misc. F480 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Misc. F531 (F539) (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Misc. F576 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Misc. F601a (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Misc. F635 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Notebook 1 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      Birds (page 3); What is a Species? (page 204); Revised Key to Fringillidae (page 250); Religion (page 266).
    - Notebook 2 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      First draft of the Synopsis of the Fishes of North America with Gilbert (page 1); Aggassiz (page 104); Religious Views of Scientists (page 110); R.A. Finesque (page 148); Specific names of species (page 200); Notes on fish (page 276).
    - Notebook 3 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      Agassiz (page 2); Bret Harte (page 24); Science in our Schools (page 80); Louis Agassiz Teacher (page 147); May 28, 1857 (page 199)
    - Notebook 4 (Box 3, Folder 78)
      Kaweah in Tulare (page 7); On Third and Townsend (page 29); La Yegna de Noche (page 35); Drifting (page 63); Castles in Spain (page 81); Sinaloa (page 85).
    - X1 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - X2 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - X3 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - X4 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - X5 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - X6 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - X7 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - X8 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - X9 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - X10 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - X11 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - X12 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - X13 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - X14 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - X15 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - X16 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - X25 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - X26 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - X27 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - X28 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - X29 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - X30 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - X31 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - X32 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - X33 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - X34 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - X35 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - X36 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - X37 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - X38 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - X39 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - X50 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - X51 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - X52 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - X53 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - X54 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - X55 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - X56 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - X57 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - X58 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - X59 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - X60 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - X61 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - X62 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - X63 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - X64 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - X65 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - X66 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - X67 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - X68 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - X69 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - X70 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - X71 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - X72 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - X73 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - X74 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - X75 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - X76 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - X77 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - X78 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - X79 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - X80 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - X81 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - X82 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - X83 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - X84 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - X85 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - X86 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - X87 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - X88 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - X89 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - X90 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - X91 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - X92 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - X93 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - X94 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - X95 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - X96 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - X97 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - X98 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - X99 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - X100 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - X101 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - X102 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - X103 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - X104 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - X105 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - X106 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - X107 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - X108 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - X109 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - X110 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - X112 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - X112 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - X113 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - X114 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - X115 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - X116 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - X117 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - X118 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - X119 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - X120 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - X121 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - X122 (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - X123 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - X124 (Box 5, Folder 207)
    - X125 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - X126 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    - X127 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - X128 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - X129 (Box 5, Folder 212)
    - X130 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - X131 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - X132 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - X133 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - X134 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - X135 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - X136 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - X137 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - X138 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - X139 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - X140 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - X141 (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - X142 (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - X143 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - X144 (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - XF1 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - XF2 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - XF3 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - XF4 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - XF5 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - XF6 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - XF7 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - XF8 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - XF9 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - XF10 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - XF11 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - XF12 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - XF13 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - XF14 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - XF15 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - XF16 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - XF17 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - XF18 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - XF19 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - XF20 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - XF21 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - XF22 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - XF23 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Manuscripts, Series IV-C
    - Miscellaneous bibliographic material (Box 6A, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous pages (Box 6A, Folder 2)
    - Hay's publication number 22 Ascent of the Matterhorn (Box 6A, Folder 3)
    - Hay's publication number 26 Spanish Missions in California (Box 6A, Folder 4)
    - Hay's publication number 30 (46, 243) Viverols (poem) (Box 6A, Folder 5)
    - Hay's publication number 34 Mazatlan (poem) (Box 6A, Folder 6A)
    - Hay's publication number 41 (44c) Bubbles of Saki (poem) (Box 6A, Folder 7)
    - Hay's publication number 43 Scientific Temperance (Box 6A, Folder 8)
    - Hay's publication number 52 (140, 238, 243) To Barbara (poem) (Box 6A, Folder 9)
    - Hay's publication number 53 The Message of the West (Box 6A, Folder 10)
    - Hay's publication number 55 Putting Away Childish Things (Box 6A, Folder 11)
    - Hay's publication number 57 The Religion That Will Endure (Box 6A, Folder 12)
    - Hay's publication number 59 The Conquest of Ilion (poem, for The Book of Knight and Barbara) (Box 6A, Folder 12.1)
    - Hay's publication number 62 (140c, 164, 194) Ecce Homo (Box 6A, Folder 13)
    - Hay's publication number 76 Rescue Work in History (Box 6A, Folder 14)
    - Hay's publication number 79 (329c) Lessons of the Tragedy (memorial service address in honor of Pres. McKinley) (Box 6A, Folder 15)
    - Hay's publication number 98 What California Has Done for Civilization (Box 6A, Folder 16A)
    - Hay's publication number 100 To Lady Alice Courteney (poem) (Box 6A, Folder 17)
    - Hay's publication number 108 [6 pages from Philosophy of Hope?] (Box 6A, Folder 18)
    - Hay's publication number 110 Two University President's Speak for the City (Box 6A, Folder 19)
    - Hay's publication number 114 (131, 184) The Religion of a Sensible American (Box 6A, Folder 20)
    - Hay's publication number 117 The man of the West and Roosevelt (Box 6A, Folder 21)
    - Hay's publication number 121 In Tehachapi (poem) (Box 6A, Folder 22)
    - Hay's publication number 124 Stability of Truth (Box 6B, Folder 23)
    - Hay's publication number 127 Eric's Book of Beasts (pen and ink drawings by Shimada Sekko) (Box 6B, Folder 24)
    - Hay's publication number 127 ("The Diversions of a President January 19, 1908 – February 19, 1908. Book of Bads Vol. 1") (Box 6B, Folder 24.1)
    - Hay's publication number 127 (Jordan's original watercolors) (Box 6B, Folder 25)
    - Hay's publication number 127 (Jordan's original watercolors) (Box 6B, Folder 26A)
- Autobiography, The Days of a Man, Series V
  Manuscript copy of Days of a Man and reviews of the published work.
  - Ross case, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chap. 12, house copy (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chap. 13, house copy (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chap. 14, house copy (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chap. 15, house copy (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chap. 16, house copy (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chap. 19, house copy (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chap. 20, house copy (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chap. 21, house copy (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chap. 22, house copy (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chap. 23, house copy (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chap. 24, house copy (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chap. 25, house copy (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chap. 1, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chap. 2, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chap. 3, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chap. 4, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chap. 5, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chap. 6, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chap. 7, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chap. 8, printer's copy (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chap. 10, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chap. 11, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chap. 12, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chap. 13, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chap. 14, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chap. 15, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Chap. 16, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chap. 17, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Chap. 18, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Chap. 19, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chap. 20, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Chap. 21, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Chap. 22, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Chap. 23, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chap. 24, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Chap. 25, printer's copy (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Chap. 26, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chap. 27, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chap. 28, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chap. 29, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chap. 30, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chap. 31, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chap. 32, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chap. 33, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chap. 34, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chap. 35, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chap. 36, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chap. 37, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chap. 38, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chap. 39, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Chap. 42, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Chap. 43, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chap. 44, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chap. 45, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chap. 46, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chap. 47, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Chap. 48, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Chap. 49, printer's copy (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Chap. 1, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chap. 2, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chap. 3, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chap. 4, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chap. 5, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chap. 6, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chap. 7, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chap. 8, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chap. 9, alternate version (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chap. 10, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Chap. 11, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chap. 12, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chap. 13, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Chap. 14, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chap. 15, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chap. 16, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Chap. 17, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Chap. 18, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Chap. 19, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Chap. 20, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Chap. 22, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Chap. 26, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Chap. 29, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Chap. 35, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Chap. 46, alternate version (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - miscellaneous notes and corrections (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Appendix A, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Appendix B, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Appendix C, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Appendix D, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Appendix E, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Appendix F, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Appendix G, alternate version (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Proof copy of Volume 1, with penciled corrections, used by Jordan's typist Isabel [last name unknown] (Box 8)
- Reviews of Jordan's writings, Series VI
  Clippings of printed reviews of Jordan's writings, and a small smattering of reviews written by Jordan.
  - Newspaper reviews of Days of a Man (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper reviews of Days of a Man (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Promotional material for Days of a Man (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Previews of Days of a Man (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Journal reviews of Days of a Man (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journal reviews of Days of a Man (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, miscellaneous publications (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Financial and Business Papers, Series VII
  Royalty statements; bank statements; depositors' receipts; and related papers.
  - Financial papers, 1893-1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Financial papers, 1904-1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial papers, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial papers, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial papers, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial papers, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial papers, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial papers, 1927-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Biographical Material, Series VIII-A
  Manuscript and printed biographical sketches and reminiscences. In chronological order.